RANUGAL Keep emm ... Smile ^ _ ^ '
Check it , And Rate it - --------------------
DEAD SNOW
Erlend .
Erlend ! Stop it .
Stop it , please . It 's really annoying when you keep
changing the station like that . / Aww for god sake , come on . / Hey .
Hey .
Hey guys . Here 's a good one .
There was this guy who went up into the mountains to go skiing .
This guy went up , way far up there .
Between the mountain peaks , it says here , the idiot calls for his bloodhound .
- Avalanche ! - Not very smart .
After 2 days of searching for him .
They found he had dug himself six yards down .
That 's actually quite normal .
When you 're buried in an avalanche , you become soo ... disoriented
that you have no idea which way is up .
Most people end up digging downwards . / Much to easy to
dig upwards . / Just spit , ya know . / What ?
Any of you been in the military ? / Yes . / No .
If an avalanche gets you , spit to find which direction is up .
You just gonna lie there and drivel ?
What do you mean Drivel ?
It means to drool .
- Drool ! - You owe me a coke .
If you 're trapped underneath the snow , you just spit and see which direction
the saliva is running . Then dig in the opposite direction .
I don 't remember that stuff from the military .
All I can remember is my service number .
69 . / ohhh !
- About that 69 , Martin ? - No thanks . Sorry , I 'm not interested .
Heh ... it 's you 're loss !
How about Hanna 's cousin ? What 's her name ? / Chris ?
- Yeah ! She single ? - She 's very single .
I don 't know her , but ... Hanna does says she 's ...
very single .
Hey guys , any chance of uhh ... making it through the rear door ?
You would need to spit first .
- Where is Sara now ? - I really don 't know .
She 'll get there tomorrow , or maybe tonight .
I don 't understand why she 's crossing those mountains by herself .
So , tell me about the boys coming on this trip .
Ok ... uhh ...
Martin , is the handsomest one . And he 's mine .
Oh , by the way ... what will he do ? Will he stay at the university ?
I 'm don 't really know . I don 't think he does either .
It 's not good for a medical student to be scared of blood like he is .
He 's so silly that Martin . So sensitive .
Martin 's afraid of blood and studying to become a doctor ?
Mmm hmm . / You 're kidding ! / Yeah , so .
Then there 's Vegard . He 's the boyfriend of Sara .
- Then we have Erlend . - The world 's biggest film nerd .
And Roy , the horniest guy north of the Arctic Circle .
He 's single , and he 's all yours ! / Thanks ! Nice !
- Yes ! - Aww man !
Ohh ! How does it feel to be the losers ? / This is it ?
Very good , excited .
OK , just follow the snow mobile tracks .
45 minutes or so in that direction and you 're there .
When you get there , I 'll have the bags unpacked and the cabin warm .
- Can I use my cell phone here ? - Naaa .
Haven 't had a signal in a while . / You mean we can 't make any dirty phone calls ?
Try 911 .
Good luck .
" " Mile after mile ... " after mile ... "
Hang on a second .
Hey ! Hey ! Hey ! Hey ! I got a question for you .
How many movies start with people on a ... , a trip to a cabin
without any service on their mobile ? / " Friday the 13th " is one .
Yeah , but they have no phone service because they have no phones .
" Evil Dead " 1 and 2 . / Yes , in a sense , except that
a lot of people regard 2 as a remake of 1 , only with a bigger budget .
OK , new rule : . Nobody can mention any more movies for at least one hour .
Good for me .
It 's for your own good , Erlend .
If you wanna try and have some fun this weekend ,
you can 't act like such a nerd . / Fuck you , Roy !
And there 's " April Fool 's Day " from about 1984 , I believe , that was a famous one .
- You agree ? - Eh ... yeah , sure .
Come on !
Hi !
- Aww man , my hands are frozen . - It 's so beautiful up here .
Ahh , It 's really nice here .
- So ... what do we do ? - See a movie ?
- Let 's unpack and get settled . - I got a better idea .
Go for it !
Ok motherfucker .
- Left foot on green . - Oooh .
- Ahh ... - You 've got it .
- Ouch . - Why are we playing this game for ?
Because Hollywood told us that it 's so much fun .
Right foot on red .
This has got to be the most boring game ev ... er .
- Are you kidding ? - No .
- For real ? - Yeah .
- Ok . - ' kay .
You didn 't like that ?
Let me show you the anesthetic for the Middle Ages .
- Lie down . - Lie down ?
- What are you doing ? - Hands together , please .
- Ok . - Thank you very much .
- You 're sitting on my hands . - That 's a part of the plan .
- So , close your eyes . - No !
Don 't look . / No , i won 't do it ! Come on .
- There we go . - No , what are you doing ?
- Relax . - I can 't see anything .
- Sit back . - I don 't like this .
Relax ... Relax . / I don 't like this . What are you doing ?
What are you doing ? What you ... Stop ! Come on . / What are you doing ?
Just Relax . / Get it off of me . / Relax . / I ! Don 't ! Let go !
Relax . / I can 't breathe ! Get off , I can 't breathe !
Martin !
Stop . / Yaah ?
Stop it ! , Let me ... Let me go !
What ?
- I 'm only kidding . - Why 'd you do that ?
I couldn 't breathe .
- I 'm sorry ! Come here . - No !
Huh ... OK ? Ow !
- So , uhh ... how do you play ? - Get the beer .
- Huh ? - Beer . Beer . Beer . - Beer . Beer . Beer .
Hmm ... Beer !
Hello ?
Someone there ?
- Someone 's out there ! - What ?
I saw someone !
It could be Sara .
- Wasn 't Sara ! - Sure it wasn 't a moose ?
What the fuck ! I know the difference between a moose and a man !
I can 't see anything .
There isn 't anything . Vegard is right , it 's just an animal .
That 's the way women are . They get scared by anything .
Could I have a cup of coffee ?
Who made the coffee ?
It 's organic .
- Was it good ? - No , not very .
What 's a fine group of kids like you doing in a place like this ?
Easter break .
- Ahh . Is the cabin yours ? - No , uhh ... my girlfriend 's .
So , who 's the lucky girl ?
Oh , uhh ... she 's not here . She 's on her way from lstind , skiing across ...
Coming over from lstind ? / She 's a little
more sporty than the rest of us . / Oi , oi , yoi , yoi , yoi .
Is it ... Is the terrain dangerous ?
Terrain is the least of your worries when your up there in those mountains .
I don 't suppose you small , spoilt brats could be bothered to read
a little of the local history about this area before you came snowmobiling into this place ?
Events have occurred here . Events that people prefer to keep quiet about .
During the Second World War ,
Oksfjord was scene as a vital area for the Germans .
It was a key harbor for German battleships .
A significant link for stopping the trade convoys between Russia and England .
Einsatz .
That was the name of the controlling battalion that was garrisoned here .
Unlike most places , where the Germans
got along rather well with the local population , that was not the case here .
They were commanded by Colonel Herzog ,
they made life hell for the local people .
People were tortured , beaten and mistreated every day .
Trust me on this .
These were evil , sadistic devils .
However ...
near the end of the War , they went a little too far , yeah .
The Germans realized that they were losing
and the Russians were closing in .
They entered every house in Oksfjord , and stole any valuables they found .
All the gold and silver . Took all the money , that they saw .
If anyone objected , they got a bullet in the head .
Shortly thereafter , the Germans were in for a hell of a big surprise .
Secretly , the local population had united and decided
enough was enough .
The 3000 inhabitants needed to release all their rage and anger
that had built up during three years .
So they gathered any weapons they could find .
Weapons like scythes , axes , clevers , shovels .
Anything that could crack a skull .
So uh ... when the night time fell , they attacked them .
The 300 soldiers didn 't stand a chance , and they knew it .
Some of them were killed . But uhh ...
yeah , the devil himself .
Colonel Herzog and many of his soldiers managed to escape .
They ran into the mountains .
They brought along a lot of the stolen goods . Damn greedy bastards .
The people from Oksfjord followed them , but they lost track of them up here .
In these mountains .
Where they most likely froze to death .
And that 's why ... one must tread very gently .
There is an evil ...
An evil you do not want to awake .
We better be careful . We don 't want to wake up .
I need to move along .
Remember what I said .
Yeah , we 're all medical students anyway ,
so I don 't think you really have to worry about us .
It 's too bad no one has taught us how to cure evil yet ,
I think we get that next semester .
If you stand with your own intestines in your hands , then what will you do ?
Or get your limbs torn off your body ? What do you do ?
Did they ever teach you that ?
Thanks for the coffee .
Sara ?
Sara ? Sara ?
Hello ?
Is there anyone out there ?
R A N U G A L
I have a weapon .
Shouldn 't you wait til tomorrow ?
- She 'll show up later today . - There 's no problem .
I 'm sure you 're right , but ... I have a funny feeling that something 's wrong .
- She 'll be here . - Listen .
If I 'm not back here by tomorrow ...
If I 'm not back by tomorrow , follow the snow mobile tracks down to the cars .
And go get help , Ok ?
Ok . / Ok .
I 'll find her , no worries .
- See you later . - Drive safely .
Ok boys , let 's have a clean race .
Start on my mark , and no dirty tricks , Ok ?
- Just one dirty trick ? - Not even one ! Ok .
Are the drivers ready ?
Ok . Ready ? GO !
Come on ! Wooo !
Oh , Erlend ! Wooo !
Hello ?
Hi !
Oh fuck !
Paging Doctor Hovden . Doctor Hovden to ER .
Martin , I can see you 've still got your little problem .
You won 't get much action if seeing a little blood makes you sick .
You fucking child .
How are you gonna get through six years of medical school and
when a ... when you wanna puke from a tiny cut ?
Maybe you 'd be better off being a baker .
- Who wants a Beer ? - Are you alright ?
- Yeah , I 'm fine . - Sorry .
Fuckin ' bag !
Check it out !
- Fortune and glory , kid ! - Fortune and glory .
1942 .
- Hey ! Hey ! Hey , that 's mine ... - Hey ! Ok ! Kay , kay , hey .
Let 's wait until Sara and Vegard come back , OK ?
- Lets leave it alone until then , OK ? - No . OK .
SARA !
Sara !
- Wooo ! - Yeah ! Heh ! Heh ! Heh !
" We 're are two small fine women ... "
Ok . Ok . Hey ! Hey , just take it easy , alright ?
We don 't know who really owns it .
That box has been here for 50 years .
Let 's help ourselves , cash in and pay off our student loans .
Listen , it hasn 't been there for 50 some odd years with nobody noticing it .
50 years ? More like a 100 years , I know it .
People have noticed and it 's just junk . / Huh ? Junk ? Junkie ? Junkie junk ? / Ya . / Junkie ? / Junkie ! / Junkie .
- Ok , it 's not junk . Trust me . - I wanna to take a shit .
- I 'm going to take a shit . - Good luck ! - Have fun !
Hey . Name it after me .
Y 'all . I 'll be back , y 'all .
Oh fuck !
- OK , a joke . - Oh spare me !
It 's good . It includes a lot of poop , pee and semen .
- Once upon a time , there was a poop ... - It 's important ...
There once was a poop ...
Look , there are no good jokes that don 't have poop , pee or semen in them .
Chris ?
No ...
I think it 's a good joke ? It 's funny . / You think it is a good joke !
That 's something to fall back on when you don 't become a doctor .
Standup ? I can do standup ... Erleeend !
You took a long time .
You see Chris ?
Ye-ea !
Erlend ?
Erlend , are you there ?
Fuck !
Erlend , stop it !
Erlend ?
Wanna here more jokes ? A guy walks into a bar ... Come on .
Help ! Help !
- Fuck you ! The song 's not over . - Shut up ! Listen .
Chris ?
No answer .
I called out but no one was there .
She 's fuckin ' around maybe .
I 'm not five . Don 't talk to me like I 'm a moron .
Hanna , she was drinking and she probably passed out .
- Ok . I 'll go look for her , Ok ? - Ya .
Hey , we 'll shoot her ! Heh ! Heh !
Bring it with you .
It 's that madman from before .
OK , umm ... Let 's go . Let 's go look for her . OK ?
OK , uhh ... you check the outhouse , and we 'll check around the cabin .
Shotgun ! / Hey !
Martin , can i try it ?
- Let me hold it ? - Stop bothering me .
- Please , can i hold it ? - Cut it out !
- No ! I said no . - Aww man . Is it heavy ?
A little .
- Let me try it . - Stop it ! Maybe later .
- Shush ! - What ?
- Fuck ! - Did you find him ?
I 'm carrying a shotgun ! A shotgun ! You see ? / Sorry ! Sorry !
- Ok . - Martin , look at this .
What a fuckin ' trip . This is bullshit .
Chris , you taking a shit ? Did ... did you pass out in there ?
No .
- She wasn 't there . - It 's not a joke .
- She wasn 't there . - What do you mean ?
Not in the outhouse , or behind the cabin . She wasn 't there .
- I found this bag . - Yeah uhh ... what do you think ?
- Maybe she 's inside there ? - Stop fooling !
- It 's Sara 's . - Huh ? Sara 's bag ?
- Where did you find it ? - It was in the snow . I found it outside .
I got a bad feeling about this .
We should go find her . She could be freezing to death out there .
Ok . Let 's get dressed and let 's go look for her .
Either we go look for her or she 's gonna die out there .
I 'm not going out there again , ok ? It 's freezing . / Stop bothering you .
- We have to look for her . - I 'm not go to look for .
We already looked for her . She 's no where to be found .
- No . You are not the boss of me , ok ? - What are you talking about ?
Listen . / Stop ! / Ok .. / Maybe don 't you .. / .. you want get out that . / No . / You go out that . / Would you want to be left out there ?
Ah ... Thank God !
- What the fuck ! - What 's the matter ? What 's the matter ?
- What is it ? - I saw Chris ' head . I saw her head .
There 's nothing there .
Pull !
Fuck ! The sofa . Put it in front of the door . Stay away from the windows !
- Hurry up ! Move it ! - Shit !
- Push it in there - Turn it !
Leave the fucking cushions .
Faster ! / Grab it ! Come on . Hurry up ! Hurry up !
Don ' t worry . They ... they can 't get in here .
Grab the table .
Martin ! Martin !
Nazis !
Zom ... . Zombies !
Don 't get bitten ! Don 't get bitten , OK ?
Shut up ! What the fuck can we do , huh ?
Come on let 's get to the car .
Erlend !
I told you that we should have gone to the beach .
RAN U GAL
Martin !
Martin , don 't bite !
Why is it so quiet out there ?
They 're having lunch on what 's left of Erlend .
We should do something .
- Do what ? - We can 't just sit here .
Try to find the car . Find some way out of here and get out .
Only Vegard knows the way , and the snow hid the tracks .
Alright . We have to do something .
Can 't just keep sitting here anymore and think this is just going to take care of itself .
Should we split up ?
Two of us try to find the car , and two of us stay here and wait for Vegard .
But if we leave we 'll still be attacked by those fucking Nazi monsters .
Then two go out and make noise .
Then those things can follow them while the others get away into the woods .
They can run down towards the fjord .
There are people who are by the fjord . And they can go and get help .
Who are the two lucky bastards who will be acting as bait ?
- You have to do something , also ! - Yeah .
Where are you , you fuckin ' pussies ? What are you , afraid of daylight , huh ?
Fuck , they 're gonna be really pissed ! That was a bit too much .
Come on !
Fuck !
Sara ?
Come on !
You fucking coward .
OK .
- Do you know where we are ? - No .
Not a chance .
- It all looks the same . - OK . OK
- Which way ? - Both go downwards .
- We have to split up . - What ?
One of us has to get down to the fucking car .
- We 'll go to the car together . - Liv , listen to me .
We have no chance alone , we have to go together . Please !
I mean it . One of us has to get down there to that fucking car .
Hanna , listen to me please ! We can 't . / Listen to me ! / Im to frightened to split up .
- Listen to me ! - I can 't do it all by myself !
OK . OK .
You saw what happened to Erlend .
There 's no chance if we split up .
- Ok . - We must stay together .
Ok . Ok .
- Let 's run together . - Let 's run together .
Throw it , dammit !
Are you sure this is gonna work ?
Have you ever tasted moonshine from Finnmark ?
NOW !
Yeah , hi . My name is Martin Hovden . We 're in a cabin up by Oksfjord .
We 're trapped ... we 're trapped up here , we 're being attacked . Please help us .
We 're being attacked by what looks like , looks like uhh ... Nazis from the Second World War .
By accident , we 've set fire to the cabin , and ... Hello ? Hello ?
Fuck ! The cunt hung up on me .
Of course she hung up . It sounds like you 've smoked your underpants .
What the fuck should I say to her ?
Say ... say that we 're being attacked by terrorists .
Tell them they are launching a huge fuckin ' rocket. then they 'll get here by chopper .
- You tell them that . - Good idea .
Fucking Nokia , the battery ran out . Fuck .
Come on !
We have to get to the shed . Shed ? What ? Why the fuck do you think we should do that ?
We haven 't got time for this .
- I can 't see anyone . - I 'll try and find the light .
You know , you know what we have to do , right ?
- Agree ? - Yeah .
Roy !
Here they come .
Where have you been ?
Where the fuck did you get a machine gun from ?
Well . I 've been busy .
Where are the others ?
Hanna and Liv are uhh ... they went back for the car . Try to find some help .
The others uhh ...
They 're ... ?
Watch out , behind you !
Martin !
- No , no , no ! - What ?
Remember what Erlend said ? Remember ?
Do not get bitten . No matter what you do , do not get bitten .
- Then you will become ... - Isn 't your grandfather half Jewish ?
I don 't think they would not recruit someone who is half Jewish , would they ?
You 'll be infected if ... . You 'll become like them .
Look what they did to Vegard .
I mean it doesn 't look as if they want us on their team , does it ?
I 've thought about that , believe me !
What 's that for ?
They uh ... taught us uh ... amputation , do you remember ?
What the fuck are you doing ?
Naa ! No , no , no , no , no !
Let 's gut that fucker and get the hell out of here .
ARISE !
Roy !
Run like hell !
Fuck !
Oh fuck !
RANUGAL Check it , And Rate it - --------------------